<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on From Stata to R</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on From Stata to R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020, Etienne Bacher. Built with Blogdown. Powered by indigo theme for Hugo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Master&#39;s thesis with R Markdown and Bookdown</title>
      <link>/posts/tips-and-tricks-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tips-and-tricks-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Why bookdown? LaTeX packages and commands Titlepage, acknowledgements and abstract Include LaTeX files in YAML Summary   I finished my Master’s thesis very recently, and I wrote it with R Markdown, and more precisely with the bookdown package. It was really comfortable to do absolutely everything with R: data treatment, use of econometric methods, redaction with chunk of codes, and even the slides for the presentation! However, I have also spent a non-negligible part of my time trying to have a correct layout, essentially for the first pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do when your code doesn&#39;t work?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-to-do-when-your-code-does-not-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-to-do-when-your-code-does-not-work/</guid>
      <description>As Jenny Bryan said, one of the first things people do when there is a problem with the code is run it a second time. But in 95% of the cases (in my small programming experience), this does not solve the problem, and I realized I developed a small pattern of reactions when I am in this situation.
Read the error message This may seem obvious since this is the first thing we see when there is an error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My application for the Shiny Contest (2020)</title>
      <link>/posts/my-app-for-shiny-contest-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-app-for-shiny-contest-2020/</guid>
      <description>One of the greatest things about R is the possibility to build websites quite easily with R Shiny. I started to create apps with Shiny almost immediately after having discovered it. This was in May last year and two months later I thought it would be a great idea to build an app to treat more easily World Bank data. Indeed, in my field, World Development Indicators (WDI) are often used and I thought it would be useful to have a graphical interface where we can import and treat these indicators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite shortcuts in RStudio</title>
      <link>/posts/my-favorite-shortcuts-in-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-favorite-shortcuts-in-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>Currently working on my master’s thesis, I spend almost half on my day on R (the other half being spent reading articles). I have learnt a few very useful shortcuts by reading blog posts or free R books here and there and I have decided to make a small list of those I use most.
“Ctrl+Shift+Enter”: run the whole script This combination will run all of your script, wherever the mouse is in the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First contact with the data on R</title>
      <link>/posts/first-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first-contact/</guid>
      <description>Files used and organization of the project Import data Merge dataframes Clean the data Descriptive Statistics Plots    Note:  In this and future articles, you will see some arrows below R code. If you click on it, it will display the Stata code equivalent to the R code displayed. However, since those are two different softwares, they are not completely equivalent and some of the Stata code may not fully correspond to the R code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should move from Stata to R</title>
      <link>/posts/why-moving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/why-moving/</guid>
      <description>Before going into the details about studying economics with R, it makes sense to explain why you should use R compared to Stata. Before I start, please note that I have been using Stata occasionally for about a year whereas I spend much more time on R so I may forget some features that Stata has and that I am not aware of. However, I believe that what I have made with Stata corresponds to most Master students’ experiences, e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>