<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>From Stata to R</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on From Stata to R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First contact with the data on R</title>
      <link>/posts/first-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first-contact/</guid>
      <description>Note:  In this and future articles, you will see some arrows below R code. In you click on it, it will display the Stata code equivalent to the R code displayed. However, since those are two different softwares, they are not completely equivalent and some of the Stata code may not fully correspond to the R code. Consider it more like a reference point not to be lost rather than like an exact equivalent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should move from Stata to R</title>
      <link>/posts/why-moving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/why-moving/</guid>
      <description>Before going into the details about studying economics with R, it makes sense to explain why you should use R compared to Stata. Before I start, please note that I have been using Stata occasionally for about a year whereas I spend much more time on R so I may forget some features that Stata has and that I am not aware of. However, I believe that what I have made with Stata corresponds to most Master students&amp;rsquo; experiences, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a French student doing a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in economics. I love R and its flexibility and I think that students in university should learn R. However, R has a steeper learning curve than Stata. Therefore, this blog aims to facilitate the transition from Stata to R for students in economics. The content you can find on it may help students or professionals in other domains but the topics will be focused on economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can contact me by email at etienne.bacher@orange.fr. You can write to me in English or in French if you prefer (I&amp;rsquo;m French too).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>